# JULIAN MENDOZA

☑ julianjohnmendoza@gmail.com 📞 6132009869 👂 Ottawa, ON. K2C 1J9 in julianjohnmendoza 🗘 julianmendoza

# **Summary**

Software Engineering student offering a strong foundation in software architecture and design. Primarily experienced in object-oriented programming; developing and testing code in Java. Adequate knowledge of project management and software development lifecycles. Passionate teacher and learner; Teaching Assistant for the Systems and Computer Engineering department at Carleton University for four semesters.

### Education

Carleton University Sept. 2017 - Present

B. Eng Software Engineering 2022 Fourth-year Student CGPA: 10.69/12

Attained Dean's Honor List throughout all semesters

# **Employment**

Canada Revenue Agency (CRA), IT Developer (Part-Time), 875 Heron Road

Jan. 2020 - Apr. 2020

- Team member of the Strategic Engineering & Technology Integration Division Agile environment
- Conducted research on applications of cloud technology achieved a certificate on Azure Fundamentals
- Designed a a web-based dashboard using a micro-front end architecture (SPA) in Angular 8
- Implemented quick, responsive and eye-catching modules using Leaflet.js & Chart.js
- Database management done in PostgreSQL

Carleton University, Teaching Assistant, 1125 Colonel By Dr

Sept. 2019 - Present

Courses: Fundamentals of Engineering I | Algorithms and Data Structures | Computation and Programming | Object-Oriented Software Development

- Interactive learning environment during lab sessions
- · Dedicated time each week to understand the material and provide student success
- Ability to mark assignments promptly and give constructive feedback
- Received positive criticism from students in adapting to online teaching
- Demonstrate fundamental programming concepts in real-time via Discord

## Projects

#### **Elevator System Simulator**

Jan. 2020 - Apr. 2020

- Designed an elevator system to tackle concurrency issues in Java
- Implement concurrent design strategies
- Used basic network protocols to communicate via LAN
- Source code available at: https://github.com/JulianMendoza/ElevatorProject

#### Software Design Project

Sept. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Object-Oriented design of the board game, JumpIN™
- Features a solver using a min/max algorithm, a modern GUI design and a level loader and builder
- Source code available at: <a href="https://github.com/JulianMendoza/JumpIN">https://github.com/JulianMendoza/JumpIN</a>

#### Skills

**PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:** Java, C, C++, Python 3, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MATLAB, Angular 8, SQL, Maven **APPLICATIONS:** GitHub, Eclipse, Wireshark, Adobe Photoshop, Visual Studio Code, Unix, HTTP, Unix systems, IntelliJ **COMMUNICATION:** English, French

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT: Software Architecture, Network Security, Software Validation, Project Management, UML